<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://www.tei-c.org/release/xml/tei/custom/schema/relaxng/tei_all.rng" type="application/xml"
	schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
  <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Letter from Helen Winlock to Mother, Maine</title>
         </titleStmt>
         <publicationStmt>
            <p>Publication Information</p>
         </publicationStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <p>Information about the source</p>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
  </teiHeader>
  <text>
      <body>
         <p><address rend="printed">
            <addrLine>Pigeon Hill</addrLine>
         </address></p>
         <p><address rend="printed">
            <addrLine>North Haven, Maine</addrLine>
         </address></p>
         <p>Dearest <persName ref="#Chandler_Mrs">mother</persName></p>, 
            <p>When I think what I have to tell
            you it nearly makes me cry but I am 
            so happy that I manage to refrain and 
            get sort of hysterical in consequence. The 
            point of it is that I am engaged to <persName ref="#Winlock_Herbert">Herbert</persName>
            and there is no doubt about it that we 
            each can make the other bubble with
            delight. I hope you like him. I think 
            he has changed a good deal in the 
            last four years so he probably has 
            a lot since he went to college </p> 
         <pb n="2"/> 
            <p>any way we seem to fit in together very 
            handily and the sun shines every day 
            even in cloudy weather. It makes me
            feel benign and delighted with everything 
            and please like him for my sake 
            even if you don't for his. However
            I have no reason to believe you dont 
            except that mother said you had
            picked out Paul who doubtless would 
            have done as well had the spark 
            been kindled but there's the rut. 
            Any way I am contented so is <persName ref="#Winlock_Herbert">Herbert</persName>
            which is the chief thing. Don't</p> 
            <pb n="3"/> sideways 
            <p>tell any body till you see us as we have been waiting 
            to have it all out with you first. But before I finish 
            I must say that it changes everything from gloom 
            to glamor and I am what is known as radiant 
            and I love everybody and you one of the most. That is the hard part of it you
            just coming back after so long a time away and I on the point of leaving 
            but while we are together lets make the most of it. 
            It will be the best thing possible to have you back 
            again and the family are counting the moments.</p>
         <pb n="4"/> 
            <p>Its a big thing, what I am going to do 
            and I hadn't got quite settled in
            my mind about it yet except its the 
            only thing for me.</p> 
            <p>I am writing this at the Bruditchs. Mea sends her best. Mrs B. has had
            the ceiling lowered in this room so as
            not to offend your exquisite eyes for 
            proportion and we all will be waiting on
            the wharf to greet you. 1000 kisses 
            from <persName ref="@#Winlock_Helen">Helen</persName> your lovingest sister.
            
               <date when="1912-08-17">Aug 17</date>.</p>
      </body>
  </text>
</TEI>
